Chioma Theresa Nwabugwu

I am a product engineer that solves technical problems without losing sight of why the product exists. I have two years experience working with JavaScript, building internal tools and working on digital products across the FinTech and Education Spaces. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment.

- 28 Fameshe Kehinde Street, Ilasan Lekki, Lagos State, Nigeria
- +2347039379012
- A chiomanwabugwu12@gmail.com
- github.com/chiomaT
- in linkedin.com/in/chiomaT

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Lagos — Full stack Software Engineer

October 2021 - PRESENT

- Working on Client Projects and Building Internal tools primarily with TypeScript and the MERN Stack.
- Serving as a Technical Instructor for Beginner Node.js Engineers.
- Recent projects I've been involved in include converting an application built with JavaScript to TypeScript.
- A member of a team that developed a web based Crypto Bank and wallet application.
- Built useable react components and styled with Tailwind.
- Managed state and HTTP requests with Axios and Redux.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.
- Built projects with Nodejs, React.js and JavaScript.
- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.

CleanAce, Lagos — Customer Relationship Manager

JUNE 2021- NOVEMBER 2021

- Implement customer analysis to identify trends and opportunities to generate revenue
- Manage customer service and support teams to address customer complaints relating to products and services
- Use social media to engage with customers
- Collaborate with marketing teams to personalize marketing interactions.

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Jira
- Docker
- Version Control with Git
- Test-Driven Development

EDUCATION

Micheal Okpara University Of Agriculture — B.sc

OCTOBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Second Class Lower - Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science From Micheal Okpara University Of Agriculture.

PROJECTS

Star Wars Characters:

A landing page where users can find different Star Wars characters with descriptions for each character.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS and JavaScript .

Link: https://chioma-star-wars.netlify.app/

Expense tracker:

A landing page where users can manage and keep track of their budget and expenses.

Technologies Used - React

Link: https://tes-expense-tracker.netlify.app/

Reading List:

A landing page where users can view a list of books, chose their favorite books and also view details related to the author of each book, lastly a user can be able to add books to the journal in a case where the where user is a writer.

Technologies Used - Nodejs, express, React, Mongodb, graphql

Link: https://tes-expense-tracker.netlify.app/

CERTIFICATION

Scrum Fundamentals Certified.